<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~files/feed-premium.xsl"?>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                             
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:feedpress="https://feed.press/xmlns" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <feedpress:locale>en</feedpress:locale>
    <atom:link rel="self" href="http://feeds.dzone.com/home"/>
    <atom:link rel="hub" href="http://feedpress.superfeedr.com/"/>
    <title>DZone.com Feed</title>
    <link>https://dzone.com</link>
    <description>Recent posts on DZone.com</description>
    <item>
      <title>Ad-Hoc YAML DSLs and Productivity</title>
      <link>https://dzone.com/articles/ad-hoc-yaml-dsls-and-productivity?utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_source=feedpress.me&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+dzone</link>
      <description>&lt;p pid="1"&gt;One of my frustrations with the DevOps and cloud infrastructure tools is that most of them are badly designed DSLs that eschew all features of modern programming languages. Things like modules, data structures, functions, imperative control flow constructs, debuggers, linters, standard versioning/deployment practices, and rich library ecosystems are all missing. Of course, it is hard to do any real work without these features so the folks using these tools at some point come to the same conclusion and re-invent non-standard analogs to get by. The re-invention usually ends up being some kind of templating system built with a real language. Two obvious examples I can think of are Ansible with its Jinja templating and Terraform with its own ad-hoc variable interpolation mechanism that I presume is built on top of Go's templating features. Oh and I almost forgot Kubernetes and Helm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p pid="2"&gt;The arguments the tool designers bring up for why they made yet another DSL are usually some variation of &amp;quot;YAML or FooBarLang is declarative and so it reduces complexity&amp;quot;. On the surface, this seems to make sense because declarative solutions, in theory, reduce complexity by hiding more details but when you start actually trying to solve problems the shortcomings become obvious. When real-world use cases are brought up along with the shortcomings of the tool to address them the response ends up being some variation of &amp;quot;You're using the tool wrong&amp;quot;. Again, this kinda makes sense until you dig deeper and realize that it's not really an answer. Tools must always be subordinate to human intentions. If a tool can not accomplish a goal or requires extraordinary workarounds then it's not the user's fault and the logical conclusion is that the tool is badly designed. If I want to write a loop and can't for some reason then that's a lack of foresight on the tool designer's part and not my problem. There could be several valid reasons I'd want to use a loop (or recursion) but because DSLs are not really programming languages I don't have any real recourse other than to figure out how to work around the limitation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <category>devops</category>
      <category>software development</category>
      <category>kubernetes</category>
      <category>golang</category>
      <category>ansible</category>
      <category>dsl</category>
      <category>terraform</category>
      <category>jinja</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 19:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/2559228</guid>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=10654180&amp;w=600"/>
      <dc:creator>David Karapetyan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spring Boot 2 RESTful API Documentation With Swagger 2 Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://dzone.com/articles/spring-boot-2-restful-api-documentation-with-swagg?utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_source=feedpress.me&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+dzone</link>
      <description>&lt;p pid="140"&gt;In this article, we will discuss how to use &lt;em&gt;Swagger 2&lt;/em&gt; for a Spring Boot 2 RESTful API Documentation. For this article, we will use the &lt;em&gt;Springfox&lt;/em&gt; implementation of the &lt;em&gt;Swagger 2&lt;/em&gt; specification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p pid="141"&gt;As we know that &lt;a href="http://www.javaguides.net/p/spring-boot-tutorial.html" target="_blank"&gt;Spring Boot&lt;/a&gt; makes developing RESTful services ridiculously easy — and using &lt;a href="https://swagger.io/" target="_blank"&gt;Swagger&lt;/a&gt; makes documenting your RESTful services easy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <category>tutorial</category>
      <category>integration</category>
      <category>spring boot</category>
      <category>spring boot 2</category>
      <category>rest apis</category>
      <category>swagger 2</category>
      <category>restful api documentation</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 18:05:03 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/2559278</guid>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=10654447&amp;w=600"/>
      <dc:creator>Ramesh Fadatare</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 Machine Learning, Deep Learning, and Data Science Courses for Beginners (Python and R)</title>
      <link>https://dzone.com/articles/top-10-machine-learning-deep-learning-and-data-sci?utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_source=feedpress.me&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+dzone</link>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Data Science, Machine Learning, Deep Learning, and Artificial Intelligence are really hot at this moment and offering a lucrative career to programmers with high pay and exciting work. It's a great opportunity for programmers who are willing to learn these new skills and upgrade themselves. It's also important from the job perspective because Robots and Bots are getting smarter day by day, thanks to these technologies and most likely will take over some of the jobs which many programmers do today. Hence, it's important for software engineers and developers to upgrade themselves with these skills. Programmers with these skills are also commanding significantly higher salaries as data science is revolutionizing the world around us. &lt;a href="https://javarevisited.blogspot.com/2018/02/top-10-highest-paying-technical-jobs-programmers-software-developers.html#axzz58Gi5STbU" target="_blank"&gt;Machine Learning specialist&lt;/a&gt; is one of the top paid technical jobs in the world. However, most developers and IT professionals are yet to learn these valuable set of skills.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;For those, who don't know what is a Data Science, Machine Learning, or Deep Learning, they are very related terms with all pointing towards machine doing jobs which is only possible for humans till date and analyzing the huge set of data collected by modern day application.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <category>python</category>
      <category>machine learning</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>data science</category>
      <category>deep learning</category>
      <category>r</category>
      <category>tensorflow</category>
      <category>sci-kit learn</category>
      <category>data science courses for programmers</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 18:04:01 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/2559844</guid>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=10654256&amp;w=600"/>
      <dc:creator>Javin Paul</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why the Instance Variable of the Super Class Is Not Overridden in the Sub Class</title>
      <link>https://dzone.com/articles/why-instance-variable-of-super-class-is-not-overri?utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_source=feedpress.me&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+dzone</link>
      <description>&lt;p pid="1"&gt;When we create a variable in both parent and child classes with the same name and try to access it using a parent's class reference, which is holding a child class's object, then what do we get?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p pid="2"&gt;In order to understand this, let us consider the example below where we declare a variable&amp;nbsp;&lt;code&gt;x&lt;/code&gt;&lt;span id="_tmp_pre_1"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;with the same name in both&amp;nbsp;&lt;code&gt;Parent&lt;/code&gt;&lt;span id="_tmp_pre_2"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;code&gt;Child&lt;/code&gt;&lt;span id="_tmp_pre_3"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;classes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <category>java</category>
      <category>tutorial</category>
      <category>overriding</category>
      <category>method overriding</category>
      <category>variable hiding</category>
      <category>sub class</category>
      <category>super class</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 18:02:02 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/2560979</guid>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=10654972&amp;w=600"/>
      <dc:creator>Naresh Joshi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adding Off Canvas Layout to a Visual Builder Application [Video]</title>
      <link>https://dzone.com/articles/adding-off-canvas-layout-to-a-visual-builder-appli?utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_source=feedpress.me&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+dzone</link>
      <description>&lt;p pid="1"&gt;Off Canvas layout is a common UI pattern for modern applications, especially on mobile devices. The concept is aimed at saving space on your page, allowing you to pop out a &amp;quot;drawer&amp;quot; of additional information. This helps reduce clutter on the main page but still provide access to important data when needed without leaving the page context. You can see an example of the runtime behavior at the top of this post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p pid="2"&gt;Oracle JET provides this type of &amp;quot;off-canvas&amp;quot; behavior as a built in component, and they have a demo of it working as part of the &lt;a href="https://www.oracle.com/webfolder/technetwork/jet/jetCookbook.html?component=offcanvas&amp;amp;demo=basic" target="_blank"&gt;cookbook here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <category>tutorial</category>
      <category>web dev</category>
      <category>ui</category>
      <category>canvas</category>
      <category>front-end development</category>
      <category>oracle jet</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 18:02:01 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/2559231</guid>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=10653848&amp;w=600"/>
      <dc:creator>Shay Shmeltzer</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best of DZone: R Tutorials for Big Data</title>
      <link>https://dzone.com/articles/best-of-dzone-python-and-r-for-big-data?utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_source=feedpress.me&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+dzone</link>
      <description>&lt;p pid="1"&gt;R is one of the most popular languages among data scientists today for all sorts of operations. From data cleaning to data streaming to data visualization, R can be a powerful tool. In this post, we take a look at the best-performing R posts in the history of DZone, mixed in with some of the most exciting new tutorials of 2018.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 pid="3"&gt;R Tutorials on DZone&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;p itemprop="headline" pid="9"&gt;&lt;a href="https://dzone.com/articles/learn-r-how-create-data-frames" target="_blank"&gt;Learn R: How to Create Data Frames Using Existing Data Frames&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;Ajitesh Kumar. Short and sweet, this post demonstrates six different pieces of R code (5 of which are only one line) that allow data scientists and developers to extract data from previously developed data frames.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <category>big data</category>
      <category>data science</category>
      <category>r</category>
      <category>data analysis with r</category>
      <category>r tutorials</category>
      <category>r tutorials for beginners</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 18:01:02 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/2556183</guid>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=10655914&amp;w=600"/>
      <dc:creator>DZone_Jordan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graphs in RavenDB: Real World Use Cases</title>
      <link>https://dzone.com/articles/graphs-in-ravendb-real-world-use-cases?utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_source=feedpress.me&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+dzone</link>
      <description>&lt;p pid="1"&gt;&lt;a href="https://ayende.com/blog/Images/Open-Live-Writer/Graphs-in-RavenDB-Real-world-use-cases_FF88/image_2.png"&gt;&lt;img align="right" alt="image" border="0" class="fr-fin fr-dib" height="439" src="https://ayende.com/blog/Images/Open-Live-Writer/Graphs-in-RavenDB-Real-world-use-cases_FF88/image_thumb.png" title="image" width="543" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I talked a lot about how graph queries in RavenDB will work, but one missing piece of the puzzle is how they are going to be used. I’m going to use this post to discuss some of the options that the new features enable. We’ll take the following simple model, issue tracking. Let’s imagine that a big (secret) project is going on and we need to track down the tasks for it. On the right, you have an image of the permissions graph that we are interested in.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p pid="2"&gt;The permission model is pretty standard I think. We have the notion of users and groups. A user can be associated to one or more groups. Groups memberships are hierarchical. An issue’s access is controlled either by giving access to a specific user or to a group. The act of assigning a group will also allow access to all the group’s parents and any user that is associated to any of them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <category>database</category>
      <category>tutorial</category>
      <category>graph database</category>
      <category>ravendb</category>
      <category>use cases</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 18:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/2560167</guid>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=10654364&amp;w=600"/>
      <dc:creator>Oren Eini, CEO RavenDB</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Buy or Build</title>
      <link>https://dzone.com/articles/buy-or-build?utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_source=feedpress.me&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+dzone</link>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;One question that I hear a lot of people asking is whether they should buy or build the software that they need to run their enterprise. This is often a difficult question to answer. One thing I can say having lived through many major software purchases is that the main cost was understanding a system that was purchased and that cost of understanding turned out to be far greater than expected. Large, expensive software products are often more costly to purchase then the price tag would indicate.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;If you can gain a competitive edge through embodying it in software then it's almost always better to build rather than to buy. This applies to entire products. Technology companies are sometimes purchased because of their customer base or inroads into a particular market segment or any number of other reasons. Of course, I'm not talking about off-the-shelf software. I'm talking about integrating essential components that were not developed in-house.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <category>open source</category>
      <category>agile</category>
      <category>custom software</category>
      <category>build or buy</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 17:01:02 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/2560227</guid>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=10655850&amp;w=600"/>
      <dc:creator>David Bernstein</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Write Browser Compatible JavaScript Using Babel</title>
      <link>https://dzone.com/articles/write-browser-compatible-javascript-code-using-bab?utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_source=feedpress.me&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+dzone</link>
      <description>&lt;p pid="2"&gt;Cross-browser compatibility can simply be summed up as a war between testers and developers versus the world wide web. Sometimes I feel that to achieve browser compatibility, you may need to sell your soul while performing a sacrificial ritual. Even then some API plugins won’t work!&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p pid="3"&gt;I apologize for the mental imagery, but incompatibility issues get me riled up. All this was before I wasn’t familiar with Babel.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <category>javascript</category>
      <category>web dev</category>
      <category>browser compatibility</category>
      <category>babel</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 16:44:06 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/2559082</guid>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=10653668&amp;w=600"/>
      <dc:creator>Robin Jangu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Implement Bootstrap Responsive Video</title>
      <link>https://dzone.com/articles/how-to-implement-bootstrap-responsive-video?utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_source=feedpress.me&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+dzone</link>
      <description>&lt;p pid="2"&gt;If you are using any videos on your website then make sure they are responsive in nature. A responsive videoautomatically adapts to the screen size of the user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p pid="3"&gt;In this tutorial, you will learn how to implement Bootstrap Responsive Video&amp;nbsp;in your website.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <category>css</category>
      <category>web dev</category>
      <category>html</category>
      <category>bootstrap</category>
      <category>responsive web design</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 16:43:38 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/1500928</guid>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=4820271&amp;w=600"/>
      <dc:creator>Joy Twain</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating an Angular 7 App With ASP.NET Core: A Step-by-Step Guide</title>
      <link>https://dzone.com/articles/creating-an-angular-7-app-with-aspnet-core-a-step-1?utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_source=feedpress.me&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+dzone</link>
      <description>&lt;p pid="2"&gt;Finally, we have a new major version of Angular, version 7. The reason I use the word &amp;quot;finally&amp;quot; is not just because people were waiting for the latest major release of Angular, but also because there were quite a few rumors about the features Angular 7 would offer. Especially since the April Fool's article published with the title, &amp;quot;&lt;a href="https://moduscreate.com/blog/top-4-changes-coming-in-angular-7-0/" target="_blank"&gt;Top 4 Changes Coming in Angular 7.0&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p pid="4"&gt;The Angular team officially announced Angular 7 just a few days back, and Angular 7 has &lt;a href="https://www.telerik.com/blogs/whats-new-in-angular-7" target="_blank"&gt;introduced some pretty awesome features&lt;/a&gt;, like improvements in Angular Material, Performance improvements, and CLI improvements to name a few.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <category>tutorial</category>
      <category>web dev</category>
      <category>web application development</category>
      <category>asp.net core</category>
      <category>angular 7</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 16:38:54 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/2559852</guid>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=10647574&amp;w=600"/>
      <dc:creator>Neel Bhatt</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Distributed Event-Driven Infrastructure to Augment Your Existing API Architecture</title>
      <link>https://dzone.com/articles/distributed-event-driven-infrastructure-to-augment?utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_source=feedpress.me&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+dzone</link>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The latest Streamdata.io Distribute™ release has a number of new features, but one of the most significant shifts for the product is the move to be a containerized solution over just being a SaaS solution. We feel this shift represents where the API infrastructure space has been headed for a while now. While we still need a SaaS solution to help folks get up and running quickly, having a containerized solution reflects how API infrastructure will be delivered, scaled, and allow companies to deliver seamless API-driven solutions across their operations.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://streamdata.io/product/sdio-on-docker/" target="_blank"&gt;latest release &lt;/a&gt;of Streamdata.io event-driven infrastructure, which we now call &amp;quot;Distribute,&amp;quot; can be deployed as a Docker container. Allowing our streaming infrastructure to be deployed alongside existing infrastructure, and controlled using microservices. All the features of the new solutions are available through a set of management APIs, allowing for orchestration of the entire platform, and seamless integration with existing API infrastructure. Dramatically shifting how you can put Streamdata.io to work within the enterprise, augmenting your existing API infrastructure with event-driven solutions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <category>integration</category>
      <category>api</category>
      <category>docker container</category>
      <category>api architecture</category>
      <category>event-driven infrastructure</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 15:31:04 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/2559850</guid>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=10654409&amp;w=600"/>
      <dc:creator>Kin Lane</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NoSQL vs. SQL: Differences Explained</title>
      <link>https://dzone.com/articles/nosql-vs-sql-differences-explained?utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_source=feedpress.me&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+dzone</link>
      <description>&lt;p pid="1"&gt;A common thread in technology — or for that matter, just about anything humans attempt over time — is &lt;em&gt;evolution&lt;/em&gt;. It's not unusual, then, to see things grow and adapt as the world around them changes. That very adaptation means that sometimes older variations of our favorite tools remain, while newer variations appear alongside them to better serve certain, specific purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p pid="2"&gt;The database world is no exception. Since the days of E.F. Codd and his introduction of the &lt;em&gt;relational data model&lt;/em&gt;, we've seen data stores and their requirements grow from purely transactional models doing ACID (Atomic, Consistent, Isolated, Durable), to requiring more flexibility, ability to scale (via distributed deployment), and speed (in terms of latency and throughput). These improvements may, in many cases, be at the very &lt;em&gt;expense&lt;/em&gt; of what made RDBMS solutions preferable in the first place. But how to know?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <category>nosql</category>
      <category>sql</category>
      <category>databases</category>
      <category>rdbms</category>
      <category>comparison</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 15:31:03 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/2558840</guid>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=10654351&amp;w=600"/>
      <dc:creator>John Hammink</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Does a Hamburger Menu Belong in a WinForms App?</title>
      <link>https://dzone.com/articles/does-a-hamburger-menu-belong-in-a-winforms-app?utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_source=feedpress.me&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+dzone</link>
      <description>&lt;p pid="3"&gt;User interfaces are constantly evolving in a bid to make every user of an application a power user. We build applications with lots of great features and capabilities and we want these to be readily available and easily accessible to the end user.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;h2&gt;Is it Familiar or Intuitive?&lt;/h2&gt; 
&lt;p pid="4"&gt;When I use a piece of software there are usually three different kinds of UIs I encounter. First are the interactions I am already familiar with from other apps, such as a menu at the top, or a ribbon bar, or a multiple document interface. Second come the new things that are very intuitive as to how they are supposed to be used. This is what we usually refer to as awesome UI/UX — it's something I’m not familiar with but at the same time something that I seem to know how to use. Once such thing for me was&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pie_menu" target="_blank" title=""&gt;radial menus&lt;/a&gt;. Although they have not gained much traction, I immediately felt comfortable using one right from the word go. The third kind are things hidden somewhere in the application that are sometimes impossible to find without external help, e.g. a functionality that has a shortcut but no other way of accessing it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <category>web design</category>
      <category>web dev</category>
      <category>ui/ux</category>
      <category>hamburger icon</category>
      <category>winforms</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 15:01:04 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/2560209</guid>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=10655720&amp;w=600"/>
      <dc:creator>Ivan Petrov</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beware What You Don't Measure</title>
      <link>https://dzone.com/articles/beware-what-you-dont-measure?utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_source=feedpress.me&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+dzone</link>
      <description>&lt;div&gt; 
 &lt;p&gt;When there's an IT outage, businesses suffer. The faster you can get the business back up and running, the better it is for all involved. Let's take a look at some of the best practices for automating major incident management, and place the focus on the importance of measuring time to restore service properly. Let's take a look at some common metrics, and remember to beware what you don't measure.&lt;/p&gt; 
 &lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mean Time to Repair&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; 
 &lt;p&gt;MTTR (Mean Time to Repair) is one of the most important and most common metrics for &lt;a href="https://www.xmatters.com/use-cases/major-incident-management-mim/" target="_blank"&gt;major incidents&lt;/a&gt;. Just divide the total maintenance time by the number of incidents.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <category>performance</category>
      <category>automation</category>
      <category>metrics</category>
      <category>incident management</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 15:01:03 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/2557901</guid>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=10646271&amp;w=600"/>
      <dc:creator>Dan Goldberg</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Fake Patient Data Drive AI in Healthcare?</title>
      <link>https://dzone.com/articles/can-fake-patient-data-drive-ai-in-healthcare?utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_source=feedpress.me&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+dzone</link>
      <description>&lt;div&gt; 
 &lt;p&gt;Ordinarily, AI systems require vast quantities of data to train on, but it's increasingly possible to train algorithms on data that is largely fake. In many domains, this isn't really necessary as data is so abundant, but in healthcare, this isn't always the case, especially for very rare conditions.&lt;/p&gt; 
 &lt;p&gt;A recent &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1807.10225" target="_blank"&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; published by NVIDIA, MG, and BWH Center for Clinical Data Science and the Mayo Clinic explores how generative adversarial networks (GANs) can help to overcome a lack of data by artificially generating it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <category>healthcare</category>
      <category>machine learning</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>gans</category>
      <category>limits of ai</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 15:01:02 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/2559838</guid>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=10654243&amp;w=600"/>
      <dc:creator>Adi Gaskell</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Big Data and Artificial Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://dzone.com/articles/big-data-and-artificial-intelligence?utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_source=feedpress.me&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+dzone</link>
      <description>&lt;p pid="2"&gt;Recently, I gave a two hour lecture on &amp;quot;Big Data and Artificial Intelligence,&amp;quot; to use some buzzwords, as asked. More honestly, it will be on (new) data and (new) algorithms for predictive modeling. Slides are &lt;a href="http://freakonometrics.free.fr/ESCP.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;now online&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;footer&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/key/NXgMPXkeCge4YU" width="595" height="485" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no" style="border:1px solid #CCC; border-width:1px; margin-bottom:5px; max-width: 100%;" allowfullscreen=""&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;div style="margin-bottom:5px"&gt;
  from 
 &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.slideshare.net/charthur" target="_blank"&gt;Arthur Charpentier&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <category>big data</category>
      <category>artificial intelligence</category>
      <category>neural networks</category>
      <category>predictive modeling</category>
      <category>data models</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 14:03:01 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/2560228</guid>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=10655878&amp;w=600"/>
      <dc:creator>Arthur Charpentier</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Internal Threats Are Far More Dangerous Than External Threats</title>
      <link>https://dzone.com/articles/internal-or-insider-threats-are-far-more-dangerous?utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_source=feedpress.me&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+dzone</link>
      <description>&lt;p pid="4"&gt;In the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://ibm.biz/2016CyberIndex" target="_blank"&gt;2016&amp;nbsp;Cyber Security Intelligence Index&lt;/a&gt;, IBM found that 60 percent of all attacks were carried out by insiders that you trust. Of these attacks, three-quarters involved malicious intent, and one-quarter involved careless negligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p pid="4"&gt;Cyber thieves use personal information to launch spear phishing attacks and commit fraud with social security numbers to steal medical identities and obtain fraudulent prescriptions. IBM Security research found healthcare, manufacturing, and financial services to be the top three industries under attack, due to their amounts of personal data, intellectual property, physical inventory, and massive economic assets.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <category>security</category>
      <category>cyber security</category>
      <category>cyber threats</category>
      <category>phishing</category>
      <category>risk assessment</category>
      <category>social engineering</category>
      <category>internal threats</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 14:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/2554136</guid>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=10655052&amp;w=600"/>
      <dc:creator>Bala Guntipalli</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AWS Lambda Frequently Asked Questions for Dummies</title>
      <link>https://dzone.com/articles/aws-lambda-frequently-asked-questions-for-dummies?utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_source=feedpress.me&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+dzone</link>
      <description>&lt;p pid="15"&gt;Since a book series called &amp;quot;... for Dummies&amp;quot; was launched, people have finally come to realize how much they don't know about the particular area they thought they previously knew about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p pid="1"&gt;We've all started from somewhere. Self-learning, learning at school or even in the office at our jobs. A breakthrough was achieved when we realized that something absolutely strange to us, became quite familiar.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <category>serverless</category>
      <category>aws lambda</category>
      <category>introduction</category>
      <category>questions</category>
      <category>faq</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 13:01:04 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/2555217</guid>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=10656017&amp;w=600"/>
      <dc:creator>Nemanja Novkovic</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Success Criteria: 21 Years of Software Engineering</title>
      <link>https://dzone.com/articles/success-criteria-21-years-of-software-engineering?utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_source=feedpress.me&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+dzone</link>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
 Oct 2018: The fact that people — well, companies mostly — have been doing me the great courtesy of paying me to produce software for them for more than 21 entire years leaves me feeling incredibly lucky — and faintly horrified at just how quickly that time has passed. Increasingly often, new grads joining me in the workplace will be younger than the bugs I've left behind, so it seems a good time to pause and reflect!
 &lt;p&gt;Have I learned anything in 21 years of professional software development? Well, yeah, a whole bunch of stuff! I've been paying &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; attention!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Some of it's obsolete now, not least all the cool Excel stuff I could do before Microsoft excreted its damned Office Ribbon thing into the world thing leaving me unarmed and bewildered. But some of it could, perhaps, by particularly kind observer, be called some form of wisdom. Facts, anyway. Experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <category>agile</category>
      <category>success</category>
      <category>promotion</category>
      <category>dev career</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 13:01:03 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/2560218</guid>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=10655761&amp;w=600"/>
      <dc:creator>Brian McConnell</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Get Connected Quiz: Are You Ready to Transform Your Business?</title>
      <link>https://dzone.com/articles/the-get-connected-quiz-are-you-ready-to-transform?utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_source=feedpress.me&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+dzone</link>
      <description>&lt;p pid="7"&gt;I hope you’ve&lt;a href="https://www.ibm.com/blogs/internet-of-things/tag/getconnected/" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt; gotten connected with me&lt;/a&gt; these last several weeks. I was talking to a colleague about why I wrote these. And it really comes down to one thing: IoT is taking place all around us. Are you and your company participating in digital transformation and impacting the physical world? Or, are you just watching it happen?&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p pid="8"&gt;Thirty years ago, we thought about reducing data in the data center. Now, with IoT, we’re thinking about amassing &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; data from all sources, along with all the combinations you can now blend together for new insights. It’s a paradigm shift!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <category>business</category>
      <category>iot</category>
      <category>transformation</category>
      <category>quiz</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 11:02:05 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/2560997</guid>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=10655189&amp;w=600"/>
      <dc:creator>Chris O'Connor</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>H2O World London 2018: A Report</title>
      <link>https://dzone.com/articles/h2o-world-london-2018-a-report?utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_source=feedpress.me&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+dzone</link>
      <description>&lt;section itemprop="text"&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;At &lt;a href="http://h2oworld.h2o.ai" target="_blank"&gt;H2O World&lt;/a&gt;, the greatest minds in AI, Data Science, and mathematics gather during one huge machine learning-oriented community event. There is a series of training&amp;nbsp;and presentations focused not only at H2O.ai Machine Learning platform but also on theoretical and applied AI and Machine Learning topics in general. This H2O World in London was the biggest one so far. The whole event is organized by countless H2O makers, led by Qybare Pula, Ian Gomez,&amp;nbsp;and Saurabh Kumar.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;h2 id="day-one"&gt;Day One&lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The very first day was a day of intense hands-on training. After a morning coffee, the &lt;a href="https://www.h2o.ai/products/h2o-driverless-ai/" target="_blank"&gt;Driverless AI&lt;/a&gt; Hands-On Training started. There were over eight-hundred people gathered in the beautiful environment of London Hilton on Park Lane, waiting to try various aspects of Driverless AI on their own. The Driverless AI panel lasted for the whole forenoon, with only a small break. After an introduction to the basics of Driverless AI by H2O’s CTO &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ArnoCandel" target="_blank"&gt;Arno Candel&lt;/a&gt;, more advanced blocks on how feature engineering or NLP are handled in Driverless AI by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DmitryLarko" target="_blank"&gt;Dmitry Larko&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/sudalairajkumar" target="_blank"&gt;Sudalai Rajkumar&lt;/a&gt;. Attendees also observed Kaggle grandmasters &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/StackNet_" target="_blank"&gt;Marios Michailidis&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&lt;em&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.kaggle.com/mmueller" target="_blank"&gt;Mathias M&amp;uuml;ller&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <category>machine learning</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>conference</category>
      <category>h2o</category>
      <category>h2o.ai</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 11:02:05 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/2560187</guid>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=10654231&amp;w=600"/>
      <dc:creator>Pavel Pscheidl</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting the Template Method Design Pattern in Java</title>
      <link>https://dzone.com/articles/revisiting-the-template-method-design-pattern-in-j?utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_source=feedpress.me&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+dzone</link>
      <description>&lt;p pid="17"&gt;The conciseness of Java 8 lambda expressions sheds a new light on classic &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Design_Patterns" target="_blank"&gt;GoF design patterns&lt;/a&gt;. By leveraging functional programming, we can get the same benefits with much less coupling and ceremony – the Template method is a great example of that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Classic GoF Template Method Implementation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p pid="18"&gt;The template method design pattern is one of 23 design patterns described by the Gang of Four – utilizing it makes it easy to conform to the &lt;a href="https://stackify.com/solid-design-open-closed-principle/" target="_blank"&gt;Open-Closed&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://wiki.c2.com/?HollywoodPrinciple" target="_blank"&gt;Hollywood&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;principles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <category>java</category>
      <category>tutorial</category>
      <category>design patterns</category>
      <category>functional programming</category>
      <category>fp</category>
      <category>template method</category>
      <category>template method design</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 11:02:02 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/2558427</guid>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=10654916&amp;w=600"/>
      <dc:creator>Grzegorz Piwowarek</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Better Integration Can Improve Net Promoter Scores</title>
      <link>https://dzone.com/articles/how-better-integration-can-improve-net-promoter-sc?utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_source=feedpress.me&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+dzone</link>
      <description>&lt;p pid="2"&gt;The voice of the customer (VOC) is an IT Infrastructure Library (ITIL) &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Voice_of_the_customer" target="_blank"&gt;term&lt;/a&gt; that describes the in-depth process of capturing customer expectations, preferences, and aversions. It is a market research technique that produces a detailed set of customer wants and needs, organized into a hierarchical structure, and then prioritized in terms of relevant importance and satisfaction with current alternatives. Originally developed in the UK as a series of books to explain procedures and best practices for the IT industry to follow, many organizations adopted disciplines from ITIL in their software delivery lifecycle (SDLC) and IT operations management (ITOM) practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p pid="3"&gt;For a quicker feedback mechanism, companies are adopting NPS&amp;reg; or Net Promoter Score. NPS surveys your software end users with one simple question: “How likely is it that you would recommend this company or product to a friend or colleague?” Software-as-a-service (SaaS) platform companies collect NPS from their customer base by layering a dynamic feedback footer bar in their web-based application. One popular product called Wootric enables customer surveys inside SaaS, mobile apps or websites with a snippet of JavaScript. Either VOC or NPS allows organizations to align company efforts around customer needs, desires and willingness to recommend a product and the company behind it. Both measurements help monitor trends, improve retention, increase referrals and prioritize the feature roadmap of customer-facing software.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <category>integration</category>
      <category>sdlc</category>
      <category>itil</category>
      <category>itom</category>
      <category>net promoter scores</category>
      <category>voc</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 11:01:03 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/2558430</guid>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=10654396&amp;w=600"/>
      <dc:creator>Matt Angerer</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don't Just Think Database DevOps — Think Compliant Database DevOps</title>
      <link>https://dzone.com/articles/dont-just-think-database-devops-think-compliant-da?utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_source=feedpress.me&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+dzone</link>
      <description>&lt;p pid="2"&gt;The 2018 &lt;a href="https://cloudplatformonline.com/2018-state-of-devops.html" target="_blank"&gt;Accelerate State of DevOps Report&lt;/a&gt; from DORA specifically calls out database development as a key technical practice which can drive high performance in DevOps. It's an interesting shift in our understanding of what should be included in DevOps workflows because it moves the database from being a bottleneck in the process to being a participant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p pid="4"&gt;At the same time, however, new data protection laws are coming into play and consumers are more aware than ever before of how their privacy can be compromised. So how can the promise of releasing changes to the database faster and easier be balanced with the need to keep data safe and remain compliant with legislation?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <category>database</category>
      <category>devops</category>
      <category>automated deployments</category>
      <category>keeping data safe</category>
      <category>team-based development</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 11:01:02 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/2558397</guid>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=10654323&amp;w=600"/>
      <dc:creator>Matt Hilbert</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Acunetix Build Adds Detection for CSP, SRI, Node.js, and Ghostscript RCE Vulnerabilities</title>
      <link>https://dzone.com/articles/new-build-adds-detection-for-csp-sri-nodejs-source?utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_source=feedpress.me&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+dzone</link>
      <description>&lt;header&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Acunetix version 12 (build 12.0.181012141) has been released. This new build reports sites that do not implement Content Security Policy (CSP) or Subresource Integrity (SRI) and detects Node.js source disclosure, Ghostscript RCE, SSRF in Paperclip, and other vulnerabilities. This new build has a good number of updates and some important fixes. Below is a full list of updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New Vulnerability Checks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;New check for &lt;a href="https://hacks.mozilla.org/2016/02/implementing-content-security-policy/" target="_blank"&gt;Content Security Policy (CSP)&lt;/a&gt; not implemented&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;New check for &lt;a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/Security/Subresource_Integrity" target="_blank"&gt;Subresource Integrity (SRI&lt;/a&gt;) not implemented&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;New check for Node.js web application source code disclosure&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;New check for &lt;a href="https://bugs.chromium.org/p/project-zero/issues/detail?id=1640" target="_blank"&gt;Ghostscript RCE via file upload&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;New check for &lt;a href="https://medium.com/in-the-weeds/all-about-paperclips-cve-2017-0889-server-side-request-forgery-ssrf-vulnerability-8cb2b1c96fe8" target="_blank"&gt;Paperclip Server-Side Request Forgery (SSRF) via file upload&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href="https://nvd.nist.gov/vuln/detail/CVE-2017%E2%80%930889" target="_blank"&gt;CVE-2017–0889&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;New check for &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@Wh11teW0lf/p1-vulnerability-in-60-seconds-85ef93d42b99" target="_blank"&gt;WPEngine _wpeprivate/config.json information disclosure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;New check for Cross-site Scripting in &lt;a href="https://tools.ietf.org/html/draft-ietf-acme-acme-07#section-8.3" target="_blank"&gt;HTTP-01 ACME challenge&lt;/a&gt; implementation&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;New check for npm log file disclosure&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;New check for PHP-CS-Fixer cache file disclosure&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Multiple new WordPress and Joomla vulnerability checks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;License keys can now be updated via the Acunetix web UI&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Additional memory improvements&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Improved exclusion of parameters&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Multiple updates to existing vulnerability checks&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Improved CORS origin validation failure checks&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Improved Pickle Serialization check.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Manual Intervention was not working after a paused scan is resumed&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Scans for some sites using Digest HTTP Authentication were stopping unexpectedly&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Additional fixes for issues causing scans exiting unexpectedly&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Fixed issue causing many product update requests when proxy authentication is incorrectly configured&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Fixed: Some backup files/folders were not being identified&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Fixed: Some vulnerabilities were incorrectly reported in the site root&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Fixed issue in similar page detection causing scans to take longer than expected&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Fixed issue causing valid sessions not to be identified correctly during the scan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Upgrade to the Latest Build&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p pid="22"&gt;If you are already using Acunetix v12, you can initiate the automatic upgrade from the new build notification in the Acunetix UI &amp;gt; Settings page.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <category>news</category>
      <category>security</category>
      <category>node.js</category>
      <category>updates</category>
      <category>csp</category>
      <category>sri</category>
      <category>fixes</category>
      <category>ghostscript</category>
      <category>rce vulnerabilities</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 10:02:03 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/2560990</guid>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=10655165&amp;w=600"/>
      <dc:creator>Nicholas Sciberras</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring AWS Lambda Deployment Limits</title>
      <link>https://dzone.com/articles/exploring-aws-lambda-deployment-limits?utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_source=feedpress.me&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+dzone</link>
      <description>&lt;p pid="35"&gt;In one of our last articles, we explored how we can deploy Machine Learning models using AWS Lambda. Deploying ML models with AWS Lambda is suitable for early-stage projects as there are certain limitations in using Lambda function. However, this is not a reason to worry if you need to utilize AWS Lambda to its full potential for your Machine Learning project. When working with Lambda functions its a constant worry about the size of deployment packages for a developer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p pid="2"&gt;Let’s first have a look at the AWS Lambda deployment limits and address the 50 MB package size in the AWS official documentation which is kind of delusive as you can make larger deployments of uncompressed files.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <category>cloud</category>
      <category>serverless</category>
      <category>aws lambda</category>
      <category>ml</category>
      <category>limits</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 10:02:01 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/2555216</guid>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=10631862&amp;w=600"/>
      <dc:creator>John Demian</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Questions to Ask Before Launching Your Citizen Development Strategy</title>
      <link>https://dzone.com/articles/5-questions-to-ask-before-launching-your-citizen-d?utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_source=feedpress.me&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+dzone</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="fr-fin fr-dib" src="https://blog.bettyblocks.com/hs-fs/hubfs/askcitizendevelopment%20(1).png?t=1541773114464&amp;amp;width=1919&amp;amp;name=askcitizendevelopment%20(1).png" /&gt;Good strategy requires clear objectives, so that's always a good place to start before introducing something new into your organization. As a CIO or IT professional, maybe you're already convinced of the benefits of citizen development and ready to get it moving. But where to start first? What is your vision for citizen development within your organization? What do you hope to achieve with citizen developers and a no- or low-code platform?&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;It is likely that many people in your organization will not yet be familiar with citizen development, and more still will need to be convinced of not only its value, but also its viability. You'll have to convince them of the &amp;quot;why&amp;quot; for your pursuit of citizen development in order to educate, generate support, and keep an overall vision central for all stakeholders.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <category>agile</category>
      <category>software development</category>
      <category>strategy</category>
      <category>citizen developer</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 10:01:03 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/2560204</guid>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=10653613&amp;w=600"/>
      <dc:creator>Angela Tramontelli</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Logs, Metrics, and Tracing: Five Ways to Up Your Observability Game</title>
      <link>https://dzone.com/articles/beyond-logs-metrics-and-tracing-five-ways-to-up-yo?utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_source=feedpress.me&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+dzone</link>
      <description>&lt;p pid="2"&gt;Early on in the cloud adoption cycle, businesses and technology professionals focused more on new applications designed to deliver transformative results. Fast-forward to today, when cloud service providers are providing services to make mission-critical application delivery more affordable &lt;em&gt;if&lt;/em&gt; enterprise teams learn how to take advantage of those services. For teams who make the transition, cloud may enable frictionless consumption of services and newfound flexibility. Unfortunately, that’s a big “if.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p pid="7"&gt;Cloud has become somewhat of a double-edged sword for today’s tech professionals. For all its benefits, the cloud also brings increased opacity, diminished observability, and can present novel issues, at least in the short term. While IT expects the same level of durability, service delivery, and observability as on-prem, the cloud is an entirely different environment and requires a different approach, with new tools and new skills to master.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <category>performance</category>
      <category>software development</category>
      <category>monitoring</category>
      <category>logging</category>
      <category>metrics</category>
      <category>logs</category>
      <category>hybrid</category>
      <category>tracing</category>
      <category>observability</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 10:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/2558913</guid>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=10654277&amp;w=600"/>
      <dc:creator>Patrick Hubbard</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Create a Threat Model for Cloud Infrastructure Security</title>
      <link>https://dzone.com/articles/how-to-create-a-threat-model-for-cloud-infrastruct?utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_source=feedpress.me&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+dzone</link>
      <description>&lt;p pid="17"&gt;The practice of creating a threat model can help teams proactively understand and develop a strategy for managing the possible vulnerabilities their organization faces, instead of waiting until after an incident occurs. OWASP defines&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Category:Threat_Modeling" rel="noopener" target="_blank" style="background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255);"&gt;threat modeling&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;as “a procedure for optimizing security by identifying objectives and vulnerabilities, and then defining countermeasures to prevent, or mitigate the effects of, threats to the system.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p pid="3"&gt;SecOps teams can benefit from creating a threat model for cloud infrastructure and defining an approach to operationalizing, hardening, and automating security throughout the software development lifecycle. While it’s best to build security into the design of your systems at the outset, remember the motto: &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <category>cloud</category>
      <category>security</category>
      <category>tutorial</category>
      <category>infrastructure</category>
      <category>cloud security</category>
      <category>threat modeling</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 06:03:03 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dzone.com/articles/2560986</guid>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://dzone.com/thumbnail?fid=10655158&amp;w=600"/>
      <dc:creator>Pat Cable</dc:creator>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
